A Guide to the Papers of Nora Perry 1884-1892
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Nora Perry, 1884-1892
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7050-a
This collection consists of 10 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library on August 31, 1966.
Scope and Content Information
The papers contain a manuscript of the poem, "The Day Lily."
Letters and postcards from Perry discuss her writing and its publication, particularly of "That Little Smith Girl;" and the submission of membership and convocation fees to an unnamed organization.
Letter recipients are a Mr. Clay, S. S. McClure, and Eliza Anna Farman Pratt.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Manuscript
  - Poem, "The Day Lily," by Nora Perry. n.d., AMsS, two stanzas. 1p.
- Letters
  - Nora Perry to Mr. Clay, Providence, Rhode Island 1884 Aug 8, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.
    Sends a manuscript of one of her stories.
  - Nora Perry, Melrose, Highlands, Massachusetts, to [Samuel Sidney] McClure 1884 Oct 27, ALS, 2 p. 1 l.
    Promises to send a story soon about the length of her story in the June issue of Manhattan.
  - Nora Perry, [Russell House], Lexington, Massachusetts, to Mrs. Pratt 1892 May 24, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l.
    Complains about the discrepancy in the date by which the story is needed
  - Nora Perry, Boston, Massachusetts, to Mrs. Pratt, [Warner, New Hampshire] 1892 Jul 20, ALS, 3 p. on 2 l.
    Writes that her story is finished and that it is "the most dramatic and full of action of anything" she has even written; discusses plans for sending the manuscript of the story; desires to have a proof immediately or a copy made so that the risk to "valuable property" in long delays is minimal; wishes to make sure that [Samuel Sidney] McClure understands that she does not sell copyrights to her stories.
  - Nora Perry, Russell House, Lexington, Massachusetts, to [Samuel Sidney] McClure 1892 Jul 23, ALS, 4 p. on 1 l.
    Writes about her concerns discussed in the July 20th letter to Mrs. Pratt; discusses the manuscript and relates that she has now had it copied while waiting for Mrs. Pratt's reply.
  - Nora Perry, Massachusetts, to S[amuel] S[idney] McClure, Tribune Building, New York, New York 1892 Jul 26, APCS
    Requests a note when the package sent by American Express is received by him
  - Nora Perry, Russell House, Lexington, Massachusetts, to "Dear Sir." 1892 Aug 8, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.
    Wishes to remit her fee for membership at this time
  - Nora Perry, Russell, Lexington, Massachusetts, to [Samuel Sidney] McClure 1892 Oct 21, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.
    Request a list of the different papers in which her story is printed and a copy of the story from one of the newspapers
  - Nora Perry, Russell House, Lexington, Massachusetts, to [Samuel Sidney] McClure 1892 Oct 30, ALS, 2 p. on 1 l.
    Requests a copy of her story from any other newspaper besides the Boston Globe, specifically the St. Louis Republic; relates her displeasure at the Globe's apparent procedure to cut and, thereby, mutilate stories